Saoirse Mullan

Product Designer (UX,UI)

Belfast, Northern Ireland saoirsemullan.com saoirse.mullan79@gmail.com 07565895806

Introduction

I am a driven and enthusiastic UX designer. I design intuituve digital prodicts with a focus on creating a meaningful user experience. I work through every stage of the UX and UI design process, from conducting user research, to creating user flows and bringing them to life through interactive prototypes to user testing.

Experience

UX/UI Designer, Aflac Belfast

May 2021 - Present

At Aflac, I help create and deliver exceptional customer experiences through redesigning our front end app. I'm able to effectively translate business problems into intuitive experiences and interaction flows, while supporting the UX Coach, Product Owner and wider team on UX/UI strategy, idea generation and design. Working across the entire UX/UI process from ideation and user research to wireframing and prototyping. I value working closely with the developers on the team and place importance on conducting user research through usability testing at all stages of the design process and compiling this into our research repository, Dovetail.

UX/UI Designer, loyalBe

June 2020 - March 2021

Led the UX/UI design for a fintech app as the sole designer on a team of 3 developers and one PM. Designed the various user interfaces (websites, native apps and customer dashboard). Transformed the consumer-facing website (loyalbe.io) to more accurately support user needs and meet business goals. Designed digital and print marketing assets. My job was to improve the quality of interaction between loyalBe users and customers and all aspects of loyalBe, including at each touchpoint.

Digital Designer, Ulster University Belfast September 2019 – April 2020

Web Design Intern, Ulster University Jordanstown September 2018 – July 2019

Education

BDes (Hons) Interaction Design Ulster University, Belfast School of Art

September 2019 - May 2020

First Class Honours and Diploma in Professional Practice with Commendation.

Modules: Interaction Design, Designing with Content, UX & UI, Narrative & Storytelling, Dissertation Writing and Major Project Prototyping.

BSc Hons Interactive Multimedia Design Ulster University, Jordanstown

September 2016 - June 2019

Completed two years of this degree followed by a placement year for Year 3 before transferring for my final year.

Achievements

UX Design Institute

Professional Diploma in UX Design July 2022

Interaction Design Foudation (IDF)

Mobile User Experience Design April 2022

IDI Graduate Design Awards

Shortlist for Interaction Design December 2020

Ulster EDGE Excel Award

May 2020

Skills

- UX Design
- UI Design
- User Research
- Design Thinking
- Prototyping
- Illustration
- Figma
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Basic HTML & CSS
- Sketch
- Dovetail

References available upon request.